Previously on Gotham...
You are a cop in everything but name.
Saving Gotham's not my job anymore.
If a person comes into contact
with my blood, it changes them.
It affects every person differently.
I won! They really want me as mayor.
How did you know I would win?
I believe in you, Oswald.
Even when you don't believe in yourself.
Miss Kringle?
No, my name's Isabella.
You remind me of someone.
I'm Edward.
Nygma.
The past is the past.
I know that we can't change the past,
but there's a difference between
moving on and letting go.
Who... do you love?
Or I shoot both them,
which would be such a thrill.
Kill Lee.
I'm so sorry this happened.
Stop the press.
Tough guy Jim Gordon
sheds tear for Valerie Vale.
How you feeling?
Like a bullet went through my insides.
You don't have any whiskey, do you?
- Sorry.
- You get a girl shot
and you don't even bring her booze.
You got a lot of nerve.
I never meant for you to get hurt.
You did.
You wanted to save Lee.
I wanted to save you both.
Yeah, but you could only save one of us.
That's why you told Tetch
to kill Lee because you knew
he would do the opposite.
Oldest trick in the book.
At least tell me you caught him.
He's still in the wind. Listen.
- Vale, it's not what you think.
- It is.
You love Lee.
Which means we're done.
- If there's anything I can do...
- No.
No, Tetch was right.
You're nothing but trouble.
So...
let me get this straight.
You're about to be in
possession of some kind of...
virus?
Yes.
It's blood-based and can
be a little unpredictable.
It can take weeks for
symptoms to manifest.
Oh!
This...
is an accelerant.
Mix it with the blood...
wham... bam...
That virus'll hit 'em like a semi
going 90.
"The Red Queen."
She's a blend of psychotropic plants.
Ah, thought she'd be a big hit.
Turns out, she's only good
at putting people in the loony bin.
- I'll take her!
- Ah-ah-ah, b-b...
That stuff's... no joke.
At first, it incapacitates you. Then...
an hour into the trip...
it completely fries your brain.
Perfect.
I'm looking to sideline someone
before this evening's event.
That'll do it.
Hey, uh, what exactly are you...
planning?
This city tore my love from me,
so I'm plunging it into insanity.
- Sync and corrections by madhatters -
- www.addic7ed.com -
And that's where I
discovered my love of books.
I never thought a fractured tibia
would launch my library career.
But it did. Fun fact:
The tibia is the second-largest
bone in the body.
Second only to the femur.
You have exquisite femurs.
Morning!
The morning paper.
What time is it?
Oh, uh... it's just past 6:00.
Uh, Edward...
These past 12 hours have
been the best of my life.
When can we meet again?
What can't you have
for breakfast or lunch?
Dinner. I'd love to.
Delightful.
Meet me at the mayor's mansion at 8:00.
I understand that one is expected
to wait 24 hours before filing
a missing persons report,
but, sir, I am the mayor.
Oswald.
I am so sorry.
When you didn't come home,
I assumed the worst.
I am so glad you're okay.
I'm better than okay.
I met someone.
I think I'm in love.
Hey! Hey, you can't be down here.
Oh, I disagree.
I don't understand why
we're doing all this, boss.
Wasn't plugging Gordon's
girlfriend enough?
Jim Gordon wasn't the
only one responsible
for my sister's death.
Gotham ripped Alice from my loving arms
and turned her against me.
What better way
to make this city pay
than by spreading my dear,
dead sister's legacy?
Oh, Alice...
Well. It's quite the operation
you've got going on in here,
isn't it, Master Bruce?
Do you need a hand?
I got it.
Right.
What time can we expect Ms. Kyle?
6:00, I think.
We'll see, won't we?
She's coming, Alfred.
And, uh, Alfred...
Yes, yes. I know, uh...
I'll make myself scarce,
I'll give you all the
privacy that you need.
Within earshot.
And the lights on.
Well, I got bad news and worse.
Skip the preamble.
It was definitely Tetch
and his two dum-dums.
And? What about Alice's body?
The eggheads here have had her
body on ice since it arrived.
Her blood's frozen, but still viable.
The second Tetch heats it up...
He has himself the virus.
How the hell did he even get in here?
The old-fashioned way.
Somebody let him in. I got
an unconscious lab tech
and a missing guard.
My money's on the guard.
Shouldn't you be in
the hospital with Vale?
She's fine. Give me the rundown.
Oh, so I take it you're
rejoining the force?
I just want to help.
There's no reason I need
to be a cop to do that.
Well, as long as I'm
captain of the GCPD you do.
I'm tired of giving you slack.
Get the hell off my crime scene
before I throw you ass in lockup.
Biehl, Alban,
escort Mr. Gordon off of the premises.
If he resists, book him for obstruction.
I'll go on my own.
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Uh-uh!
No. I see that look in your eye.
Do not try to solve this by yourself.
Then help me. If Tetch
has Alice's blood,
we don't have much time.
No, I'm not gonna aid
you on one of your solo,
bullcrap, kamikaze missions anymore!
Tetch murdered four people yesterday.
He shot Vale... I can't just
let him get away with it.
Nobody's asking you to.
But Barnes is right.
Either be a cop, or don't.
What are you so afraid of?
Is that what you think?
That I'm afraid?
You know, you should go to the hospital.
Be with Vale.
And let those of us who
want to wear the badge
do our damn jobs.
You are going to cut
quite the fine figure
at the Founders' dinner tonight.
Yes. Did you know that this dinner
has been thrown annually
for over 200 years?
It was started by the
first families of Gotham.
Only the most powerful
citizens are invited.
It's a shame I don't have a "plus one."
I can't go anyway. I have a date.
With the woman you
claim to be in love with
after only knowing for a few hours?
The heart keeps its own time.
I'm partial to the purple.
The brocade brings out my eyes.
Are you sure you aren't
mistaking infatuation for love?
You did say she is the
spitting image of Kringle.
Isabella's beautiful.
And smart.
So she... bears a passing
resemblance to Kristin.
It's just the universe telling me...
Telling me I have a
second chance at love.
Where did you say she works?
The Main Public Library.
You're right about the brocade.
Do you mind if I skedaddle?
I just need to pick up a
few things for tonight.
Who am I to stand in the way of love?
The missing guard from the
lab, he called in sick.
My gut says he's lying.
Well, he's certainly no
candidate for sainthood.
Gambling, petty theft...
Might I have a word, Captain?
Bring him in.
What is it?
I just heard from the head of virology
at the Biomedical facility.
Is this about the tests they're
running on Alice Tetch's blood?
Yes, in the first trial...
One of the rats ran off the rails
and murdered the rest, I know.
Doc Thompkins told me.
But she thought it might
have been an anomaly.
I'm afraid the second
study proves otherwise.
As in the first study, the rats showed
increased strength and agility, but...
by week two...
the rats were exhibiting
manic tendencies.
Violent rage.
By the study's end, every trace of their
original demeanor had vanished.
I assume they're, uh, working on a cure.
Yes, but it could take years.
And we only have hours.
Damn it!
If this virus gets set free...
We have to find Tetch, now.
Yes, sir.
Watch closely, Dumfree.
Isn't science marvelous?
Gravity, a few heaters...
and voilà!
The last drops of coagulated blood
become cocktail mix.
Ah!
Bravo, Alice.
Truly... your best work.
- You're kidding me?
- Please, calm down.
- He said, "Kill Lee"?
- He knew Tetch wouldn't.
How?
How could he possibly have known that?
Somehow he got inside Tetch's head.
And he knew that he would do the
opposite of what he told him to.
I see. So, why would Gordon offer up
the woman he's dating
in place of my fiancée?
Mario, stop it.
We have so much to be thankful for.
I just want to move past this.
Fine.
But Jim Gordon's the reason
you were in danger to begin with.
I want him out of our lives.
Of course.
I came by to bring this to... Vale.
I got to get back to the ER.
He's angry.
I get that.
He has every reason to be.
I figured you'd be out
chasing down Tetch.
Barnes banned me.
No badge. No investigation.
That's never stopped you before.
They closed ranks.
Even Bullock.
He says I'm refusing the
badge because I'm afraid.
Jim... I know what you did
last night.
When you told Tetch to kill me,
you knew he would shoot Vale.
No, I'm sorry. That's not true.
At least have the decency
to be honest with me.
I am being honest.
I wanted to save Vale.
Bullock was right.
You are afraid.
Hello, there.
Mr. Mayor, what an honor.
How can I help you?
I am attending the Founders'
dinner this evening
and I wanted to brush up on the history
of Gotham's first families.
My chief of staff suggested I come here.
I think you might know him.
Yes. I know Edward.
We just met,
but...
well, I feel I've known
him my whole life.
How romantic.
Oh, listen to me, blathering on.
You wanted a book.
Um...
Oh.
I'm...
so glad you appreciate Ed.
Really, I should thank you
for brightening Ed's spirits.
He has been so down since
he got out of Arkham.
Edward... was in Arkham?
You don't know?
It was front page news.
I stick to books.
Don't people typically
go to Arkham for murder?
I make it a policy not to gossip
about staff, but...
Uncanny how much you look like her.
It's that swan-like neck.
Ed loves a neck.
Well, thank you for the book.
It was a pleasure meeting you.
Hey.
Hey!
The tea party was part one.
I want to have a lot more fun.
I had my way with you.
Now Gotham's up for round two.
The hell are you talking about?
Why, I'm going to dismantle
your beloved city,
from the top... on down.
And you can't stop me.
Enjoy the trip.
It's going to be a bumpy ride.
There you are.
So good to see you.
Likewise.
Come on, let's get some wine.
Watch where you're going.
Of course, Mr. Mayor.
So sorry.
Cretin.
Jim.
Jim!
Finally, sleeping beauty stirs.
Where am I?
You got dosed, buttercup.
Welcome to your hallucination.
- What are you doing in it?
- Hell if I know.
Now, we've got a lot
to be getting on with.
I don't have time for this.
See, that's the thing about
hallucinations, Jimbo.
You got to ride out the trip.
Bummer, huh?
What exactly does this trip entail?
Well, no one gave me an itinerary,
but knowing what goes
on inside your head,
I'm sure it'll be
chock-full of belly laughs.
Just kidding.
We all know fun isn't your forte.
This is where I face
my inner demons, huh?
That's up to you.
Well, go on.
Unless you want to stay in
this tiny space with me.
I'll take my chances.
Jim.
Bruce?
You don't have much time.
What are you talking about?
Bruce.
Bruce!
Where did Bruce go?
What?
Never leave your unit behind.
I have to find him.
Bruce. Bruce!
I'm glad you came.
What did you mean when you
said I didn't have much time?
I just wanted you to follow me...
so I could show you that.
Down there.
It's because of you.
Congratulations, Jim.
You did it.
You're the hero you
always dreamed of being.
Bruce...
Don't...
Your name was on the schedule.
Yeah, I told you. It was my
shift at the bio lab, but I...
- came down with something.
- The only thing you're coming down
with, pal, is ten years at Blackgate.
Hey, hey, hey.
That's no way to treat a sick man.
Listen, Sullivan,
Tetch got in using an
employee's key card.
Just show us your card,
and you're free to go.
Screw you.
I want a lawyer.
You pigs think you're such tough guys...
Honest citizens driven mad,
tearing each other limb from limb
just because you decided
that this city's security
is not your concern!
Tell us what you know
about Jervis Tetch!
- Captain! Cap.
- Aah...
Cap! Hey.
I thought I was supposed
to be the bad cop here.
A bruiser in a wrestling mask
paid me to hand over my key
card and take the day off.
Promised I wouldn't get in trouble.
Said the cops would be too busy
taking back control of the city.
And?
Tell us something that
might actually help.
He was driving a catering van.
Why would the Tweeds
need a catering van?
Wait.
What's the date?
Friday.
The date.
The 27th.
The Founders' dinner.
The archbishop, the
comptroller, the mayor,
all in the same place.
Put together a unit.
And not a word to Gordon.
A drop of blood
in each wine glass
makes madmen...
of the ruling class.
What the hell are you doing?
Saving your life. Like you wanted.
The last thing I want is
your lips on my mouth.
News flash.
Everything that is happening
is in your head.
Which means you made me give you CPR.
Just like you put me
in this really cheesy nurse's uniform.
That's easily rectified.
Seriously?
One bad encounter with Bruce, and...
I don't want to talk about it.
Fine. Just don't fall into
a monosyllabic depression
because...
We're at the next stop.
I have mixed feelings about this floor.
I'm afraid to ask.
I'm so glad you're home.
Mom thought you were gonna be late.
Ha! Mom owes me a quarter.
Mom!
We made a bet that you
were gonna be late.
Frankie had more faith than I did.
Now go on.
Take those rolls to the table.
How was your trip?
Earth to Jim.
Sorry. You just look so beautiful.
Ew! You guys are gross.
Julie, one day, you're
gonna love somebody
as much as I love your father.
- Never. Boys are dumb.
- Are not.
You feeling okay, honey?
Just glad to be here.
With you guys.
I love you so much.
Does that mean we can get a dog?
You two.
- Sure!
- Yay!
You're the best, Dad.
The best!
- Just the best, Jim.
- No...
No, no, no! No! No! Come back!
You look like you need a drink.
Jim...
Open the damn gate, Barbara.
I need to get back to them. To her.
If you're so desperate to have
Thompkins and the two kids,
why are you in that crappy
apartment playing private dick?
Let go of me. You don't
know what the hell
you're talking about.
I know you're lost.
You want to find your way home?
Play nice.
It's a long way to the basement.
So...
The little minx was a no-show.
Well, it seems a frightful shame to let
this beautiful meal go to waste.
What say we wrap it up and
have it for lunch tomorrow?
Hey?
You always bring your
butler along on dates?
Right.
I'll leave you to it.
Excuse me, miss.
You're late.
Stuff came up.
Geez. Chill.
- Alfred really outdid himself.
- I made all of it.
For you.
What's with the attitude?
You stood me up.
I got busy.
Selina, if we're gonna do this,
whatever this is,
I need you to be honest with me.
This?
Me and you.
It's weird for me.
Okay?
It's weird for me, too.
So...
are you gonna cut the cake, or what?
Of course, I didn't want to
stand in the way of love, but...
this woman would have been a disaster.
It sounds as if you did
your friend a favor.
I'm sorry, I have been talking so much.
I never asked your name.
Kathryn.
Just Kathryn.
Mm-hmm.
How did you end up at
the Founders' dinner?
If it's not rude of me to ask.
Not at all.
I'm from one of Gotham's
oldest families.
And I'm part of a group which...
oversees things.
What sort of things?
Everything that matters in Gotham.
We've had our eye on you for some time,
Mr. Cobblepot.
Who exactly are you?
We'll contact you when
the time is right.
Enjoy your evening.
Excuse me,
did you notice the rather...
severe-looking woman
I was speaking with?
She said her name...
What is this? What is going on?
I'm afraid your evening
has been hijacked,
Mr. Mayor.
I see the champagne didn't leave a mark.
I'm so glad.
For those of you who don't know me,
my name is Jervis Tetch.
I promise not to take up
too much of your time.
But the fact is, you...
are the heads of Gotham.
And tonight
the heads of Gotham will roll.
But first...
a toast.
A drink to your health.
And if we don't?
Change, my friends, is nigh.
Drink the wine...
or else you die.
Glasses down now!
Glasses down!
Oh, my...
Is that my dear sister I see?
Oh!
She's in you, isn't she?
What fun!
Shut up!
Last stop.
Don't be scared.
It's not easy to face
who you really are.
I should know.
Do you ever wish you were
the person you used to be?
Do you?
Use this.
Or don't.
It's up to you.
Good luck, Jim.
Sir...
Sir, I think you're looking for this?
Dad?
Hey!
It's good to see you, son.
I'm always losing that darn thing.
Get in. We don't want to be late.
Doctor? Doctor?
Some help.
Doctor, he's unconscious.
Dr. Calvi, he's in here.
Jim?
Jim.
This was beside him.
"Red Queen."
I've heard of this.
Get me 20cc's of Haloperidol.
- Right away, Doctor.
- Jim, can you hear me?
Jim.
Jim!
Come on, Jimmy,
it's time to go.
Something wrong?
No.
I'm just glad to see you.
I missed you a lot.
Yeah, sorry I haven't been around more.
Heard you got into some kind of trouble.
You want to talk about it?
When I was a kid,
people would tell me,
"Your dad's a hero."
All I knew is you went
to court every day,
and every night you came home
and you played ball with
me while Mom made dinner.
Then I got older
and I understood you were a hero.
Only for me, it wasn't just
that you'd been a great D.A.
It was that you got up day after day,
you faced down the worst
the city had to offer,
but you never brought
that home to Mom and me.
You protected us.
I wanted to be just like you.
Turns out I'm the opposite.
I destroy everything
and everyone around me.
Come on, Jimmy,
I'm far from perfect.
I got plenty of darkness inside me,
I just don't dwell on it.
Focus on the good you can
do. That's what counts.
- That's what I'm trying to do.
- No.
Been hiding behind self-righteous
lone wolf nonsense
because you're afraid.
Why is that?
The badge holds expectations.
People want a hero. And I'm not.
You know what makes a hero, son?
A man who values protecting others
above protecting himself.
A man who knows his limits
but isn't afraid to fail.
A man who knows when to ask
for help when he needs it.
Now... I-I wasn't always that man,
but damn, that didn't
stop me from trying.
- I don't know how to be that man.
- Well, sure you do.
Just got to follow the code.
What... you remember what that is?
No.
The code we Gordons promise to live by?
No. Why can't I remember?
Because you're lost, son.
If you want to find your way back home,
the answer you're looking
for is in my ring.
Ah... shoot.
It's time for me to go.
No. I want to talk to you more.
No, I can't. Someone's coming for me.
No, Dad.
No, Dad, please. Don't go. No, Dad!
I'm proud of you, Jimmy.
Dad!
Jim?
Jim, can you hear me? Jim.
Yeah.
Yeah, I can hear you.
It's Haloperidol,
an antipsychotic.
You were dosed with a pretty
powerful hallucinogen.
- It was Tetch.
- I know.
Someone saw him leaving the hospital.
You know, you're lucky.
Another minute, we would have lost you.
Thank you.
It's my job.
Dr. Calvi?
We need your signature, please.
Uh-huh.
I'll get somebody to take the I.V. out.
Half an hour, a glass of orange juice,
you'll be good to go.
So while I did...
kill my girlfriend,
who does look rather similar to you,
it was not out of malice or intent.
It was an accident that I deeply regret.
And I was not gonna tell
you this, but then...
Edward,
I know what you did.
You do?
I spent the afternoon reading
every article about you.
You know what I did and yet
you still came on this date anyway?
Well...
That's not logical.
Love isn't logical.
I've lived my whole life
inside the pages of books.
Any other men I've dated,
they didn't compare to the
lovers I spent my life with:
Anthony, Cleopatra,
Romeo and Juliet,
Othello and Desdemona.
All of whom died.
Edward,
you're the first to measure up.
You're the one I waited for.
You're not scared of me?
Of course I am.
Can you feel how fast
my heart's beating?
Well, Ed,
you would not believe the night...
Oswald, good evening.
This is Isabella.
Oh...
we have met.
Mm.
Would you excuse me?
I am very tired.
"Dum spiramus tuebimur."
While we breathe,
we shall defend.
Come in.
You busy?
Just finishing up some
paperwork on Tetch.
He and the Tweeds are
safe and sound in Arkham.
Hopefully, that's the
last we'll hear from them.
Congratulations.
You did what I couldn't. I mean that.
A humble Jim Gordon.
What do you know?
I hear Tetch sent you on quite a trip.
If it wasn't for Mario, I'd be dead.
Anyway, I'm not here about that.
I want to rejoin the GCPD.
Why the sudden change of heart?
I made a promise to
someone when I was younger.
I intend to keep that promise.
Good.
We need you here.
I need you here.
Welcome back, Detective.
It seems you left dinner
just in time.
Indeed.
And what did you think of our new mayor?
My gut says once a
criminal, always a criminal.
We'll keep an eye on him.
Judgment is coming, Kathryn.
For all of us.
www.tvsubtitles.net